<resources>
    <string name="app_name">App2</string>
    <string name="bio_app">Birzeit School for Girls was founded in 1924 by Nabiha Nasir (1891-1951) as an elementary school for girls from Birzeit and the surrounding villages. It was one of the first schools in the region. In 1930, it broadened its scope to become a co-educational secondary school, and in 1932, it was renamed Birzeit Higher School. In 1942, the name was changed to Birzeit College. In 1953, a freshman higher education class was incorporated, followed by a sophomore class in 1961.[5]  The Faculty of Information Technology was established in 2006 (later merged with the Faculty of Engineering to create the Faculty of Engineering and Technology), and in 2007, the Faculty of Arts was established. The Faculty of Nursing and Allied Health Professions (later renamed Faculty of Pharmacy, Nursing and Health Professions) was established in 2008.[5]  In 2015, Birzeit University launched the Ph.D. program in social sciences, its first doctorate program.[6] In 2016, the university was ranked first nationally in the January edition of the Webometrics Ranking of World Universities.[7] 2018 saw the establishment of Birzeit University\'s newest college, the Faculty of Art, Music and Design.[8] The university was ranked top nationally and among the top 3 percent of universities worldwide in the 2018 edition of the QS World University Rankings,[9] and it retained its position in the 2019 edition.[10]  Dr. Beshara Doumani assumed office as President of the University in August of 2021.[11]  The university was closed from 1988 until 1992 by the Israeli army.[12] The university was the last of 6 in Israeli occupied territories to reopen.[13]  In December 2021, a series of violent incidents between students of rival Palestinian factions occurred in the campus.[14] On 14 December 2021, Israeli soldiers and Shin Bet arrested a number of students allegedly involved with a Hamas cell, and accused of funneling money and organizing rallies in support of the organization, as well as incitement.[15] The same day, hundreds of students took part in a Hamas parade on campus to mark the movement\'s founding anniversary.[14][15][16] Some students also attacked the university\'s security guards.[14]  On 10 January 2022, an undercover Israeli military unit known as the Mista\'arvim stormed the university, shooting one student in the leg and detaining four other student activists.</string>
</resources>